window.__QUIZ_DATA__=[{"id":15284,"question":":Higher genetic diversity","correct_answer":"May help a population to cope better with future environmental changes","wrong_answers":["Is usually apparent in small populations","Has no effect on future population's persistence","Has usually a negative effect on future population's persistence"]},{"id":15285,"question":"The term 'species diversity' is composed of:","correct_answer":"Number of individuals (abundance) and number of species","wrong_answers":["Number of individuals (abundance) only","Number of species only","(Number of genes and number of individuals (abundance)"]},{"id":15286,"question":"The 'snowball effect' in the context of the relationship between species richness and ecosystem functionality means that:","correct_answer":"Losing a particular function due to reduced species richness can lead to loosing other functions","wrong_answers":["Losing a particular function due to reduced species richness can lead to adding other functions","Losing a particular function due to reduced species richness has no effect on other functions","Losing a particular function due to reduced species richness has a positive effect on other functions"]},{"id":15287,"question":"In the context of our section, stability is defines as:","correct_answer":"The ability of an ecosystem to resist changes in the presence of perturbations","wrong_answers":["The inability of an ecosystem to resist changes in the presence of perturbations","The ability of an ecosystem to move from one state to another","The ability of an ecosystem to change in the presence of perturbations"]},{"id":15288,"question":"Which of the sentences below is incorrect:","correct_answer":"Degraded ecosystem has no effect on the extinction probability of the remaining species","wrong_answers":["Species extinction may cause a reduction in the functionality of an ecosystem","Healthy ecosystems can buffer against local extinctions to maintain local stability","Habitat loss in an already degraded ecosystem may lead to local instability"]},{"id":15289,"question":"Most species in the world are?","correct_answer":"Insects","wrong_answers":["Plants","Reptiles","Birds"]},{"id":15290,"question":"Usually, smaller species have:","correct_answer":"More restricted ecological requirements","wrong_answers":["Less restricted ecological requirements","Similar ecological requirements as larger species","Wide ecological requirements"]},{"id":15291,"question":"In the species-area relationship curve, the 'z' parameter reflects:","correct_answer":"The slope of the line on a logarithmic scale","wrong_answers":["The intercept of the line with the Y axis","The intercept of the line with the x axis","The decrease of species richness with area"]},{"id":15292,"question":"Larger areas, usually:","correct_answer":"Harbor higher heterogeneity","wrong_answers":["Are very homogeneous","Have lower heterogeneity","Are dominated by one large habitat"]},{"id":15293,"question":"As a rule of thumb, for nature conservation, we should strive for:","correct_answer":"Large and highly heterogeneous areas with greater connectivity","wrong_answers":["Small and highly heterogeneous areas with greater connectivity","Large and highly homogeneous areas with greater connectivity","Large and highly homogeneous areas with lower connectivity"]},{"id":15294,"question":"Species extinction:","correct_answer":"Is a natural part of the evolutionary process","wrong_answers":["Is a result of the increased human influence on earth","Does not have any effect on biodiversity loss","Currently, in the 21st century, the rate of species evolution is much higher than the rate of species extinction"]},{"id":15295,"question":"The term 'Mass Extinction':","correct_answer":"Refers to events associated with much higher “extinction rates” than the background extinction rate","wrong_answers":["Refers to a mass extinction event of large-bodied species, such as the dinosaurs","Refers to extinction events which are a direct result of human actions","Refers to six geological eras in which new evolving species became extinct"]},{"id":15296,"question":"The current state of biodiversity:","correct_answer":"Only a minor portion of all existing species have been evaluated and categorized for their status by the IUCN","wrong_answers":["The majority of all existing species have been listed in the IUCN Red List as threatened, which means that they face high risk of extinction in the wild","The IUCN red list is continuously updated according to changes in species status throughout time: for example, the percent of threatened mammal species has decreased considerably in the last decade","A species is defined as extinct in the wild if no members of the species are found in the species’ breeding sites during the breeding season"]},{"id":15297,"question":"Efficient conservation efforts should:","correct_answer":"Target a range of spatial scales and different conservation units","wrong_answers":["Focus only on ecosystem restoration","Omit reintroduction projects as these are expensive and risky","Direct all research efforts to species protection"]},{"id":15298,"question":"The main advantage of reintroduction is that it:","correct_answer":"Improves the conservation of species and its ecosystem","wrong_answers":["Reestablishes the role of top predators in the ecosystem thus restoring the ecosystem functionality","Attracts public awareness to the importance of returning species that occurred during","All answers are correct"]},{"id":15299,"question":"Usually, small populations:","correct_answer":"Are prone to extinction because of the combined effect of different factors","wrong_answers":["Attract public awareness because of their role in disease transmission to other species","Have high genetic diversity which can lead to species extinction","Are spatially connected to other populations"]},{"id":15300,"question":"Which case has the highest probability for a successful reintroduction project?","correct_answer":"The released individuals are selected according to their sex and age from a permanent breeding core of the species","wrong_answers":["The release site is within the species’ historical range of distribution, where natural habitats are under development pressure","Hunting is forbidden in the site of release but is enabled in its surroundings","The population in captivity is large and individuals are released directly to the wild to acclimatize to the natural conditions without the need for habituation enclosure"]},{"id":15301,"question":"In which of the following cases should species reintroduction be avoided?","correct_answer":"The species’ natural habitat is patchy and disconnected/isolated","wrong_answers":["The species’ population in captivity is large","The species is not considered a flagship species","Hunting is regulated in the species’ natural habitat"]},{"id":15302,"question":"When is a species considered critically endangered by the IUCN?","correct_answer":"If it is spread over a relatively small range (less than 100 square km","wrong_answers":["If no members of the species are found in the species’ range of distribution over a period of several years","If it has low genetic diversity","If its population suffers from a highly transmissible disease"]},{"id":15303,"question":"What is the major aim of Conservation Biology?","correct_answer":"To maintain biodiversity throughout the world","wrong_answers":["To bring back the extinct species","To rewild ecosystems by reintroducing species","All answers are correct"]},{"id":15304,"question":"Given that species play a major role in modifying and stabilizing ecosystem functions, we sometimes consider them as:","correct_answer":"Ecosystem engineers","wrong_answers":["Ecosystem multipliers","Ecosystem services","Ecosystem changers"]},{"id":15305,"question":"Large areas:","correct_answer":"All of the above","wrong_answers":["Harbor high heterogeneity","Harbor many habitats","Harbor high species richness"]},{"id":15306,"question":"Open lands are:","correct_answer":"Areas of land without human-built structures","wrong_answers":["Nature reserves only","Nature reserves and non-protected natural habitats","Agricultural landscapes only"]},{"id":15307,"question":"The economic value of world's ecosystem services to human beings, according to Constanza and his colleagues (1997), is:","correct_answer":"An average of US $ 33 trillion per year","wrong_answers":["An average of US $ 16 trillion per year","An average of US $ 54 trillion per year","Cannot be evaluated"]},{"id":15308,"question":"Provisioning services are:","correct_answer":"Products obtained from ecosystems","wrong_answers":["Services required for the existence of the other ecosystem services","Benefits obtained from the regulation of ecosystem processes","Nonmaterial benefits people obtain from ecosystems through spiritual enrichment, cognitive development, reflection, recreation and aesthetic experiences"]},{"id":15309,"question":"The recent estimate of the number of people throughout the world that go to sleep every day without any dinner, is:","correct_answer":"1.8 billion","wrong_answers":["1 billion","0.5 billion","200,000"]},{"id":15310,"question":"How much of the earth's land area is already used for different agricultural cultivations and agricultural-related activities?","correct_answer":"40%","wrong_answers":["30%","20%","10%"]},{"id":15311,"question":"Land sparing refers to:","correct_answer":"","wrong_answers":["A clear integration between the natural habitat area and the agricultural area","A clear separation between the natural habitat area and the agricultural area","Combination of natural habitat area and agricultural fields","A subset of the land sharing method"]},{"id":15312,"question":"The term that reflects movement from one patch to another, through short-distance dispersal, in a landscape, is:","correct_answer":"Stepping stones","wrong_answers":["Long-term dispersal","Isolation","Connectivity"]},{"id":15313,"question":"Hedgerows may contribute to wildlife-friendly agriculture by:","correct_answer":"Conserving arthropod communities within agricultural landscapes","wrong_answers":["Attracting pests","Isolating different subpopulations from breeding","Ensuring clear habitat without arthropods"]},{"id":15314,"question":"CO:","correct_answer":"Blocks the oxygen from reaching the brain","wrong_answers":["Is not dangerous as it is everywhere","Is not more dangerous than CO2","Is related to global warming"]},{"id":15315,"question":"Particle motion is affected by:","correct_answer":"All of the above","wrong_answers":["The drag force","The size of the particle","The viscosity of the particle"]},{"id":15316,"question":"The drag force:","correct_answer":"Depends on the viscosity of the fluid","wrong_answers":["Depends on the viscosity of the particle","Depends on particle color","Does not depend on particle density"]},{"id":15317,"question":"The characteristic time τ:","correct_answer":"Is mainly a function of particle size","wrong_answers":["Reflects the reaction time for changes in flow velocity","Is very small for large particles","Does not depend on fluid viscosity"]},{"id":15318,"question":"According to the exercise solved in the video presentation, at t=τ:","correct_answer":"All of the above","wrong_answers":["The particle velocity decreased from 1 m/s to 0.37 m/s","If the initial velocity was 10 m/s it would reduce to 3.7 m/s","If it was τ/2, it would have been 0.61 m/s"]},{"id":15319,"question":"Increasing the emitted particle size:","correct_answer":"Reduces the probability of it penetrating deep into the lungs","wrong_answers":["Increases the risk associated with the particle","Increases its time in the air","Increases the difficulty of capturing it"]},{"id":15320,"question":"Nanoscale particles:","correct_answer":"Can reach the brain","wrong_answers":["Do not constitute any risk at all","Cannot attach to the surface of the respiratory system","Are not formed from engines"]},{"id":15321,"question":"Grouping of smoke particles:","correct_answer":"All of the above","wrong_answers":["May lead to their coagulation","May reduce the number of particles","May enable better filtration and reduce air pollution"]},{"id":15322,"question":"The effects of air pollution can be reduced if:","correct_answer":"Fewer smoke particles are emitted","wrong_answers":["More NO2 is emitted from combustion","We decrease emitted particles’ size","The emitted particles have less mass"]},{"id":15323,"question":"We can group and make particles larger, if:","correct_answer":"All of the above","wrong_answers":["We take advantage of the characteristic time τ","We induce velocity variation in the vehicle exhaust system","We design an exhaust system according to a mathematical model"]},{"id":15324,"question":"How many people on earth suffer from water availability and water sanitation issues?","correct_answer":"A few Billions","wrong_answers":["About 100 Million","Not many","None of the above"]},{"id":15325,"question":"Greywater is typically defined as:","correct_answer":"Domestic wastewater excluding the wastewater stream from toilets","wrong_answers":["Domestic wastewater","Municipal wastewater excluding the wastewater stream from toilets","Wash basin water"]},{"id":15326,"question":"Some health regulatory agencies object to on-site greywater reuse for toilet flushing:","correct_answer":"Because it often contains pathogens, thus may lead to the spread of diseases","wrong_answers":["In order to protect citizens, as greywater reuse is often too expensive","Because it may introduce pathogens to nearby water sources","Agencies do promote greywater reuse in general, and for toilet flushing in particular, as it saves precious water"]},{"id":15327,"question":"Could the practice of reusing raw greywater for irrigation negatively impact irrigated soil?","correct_answer":"Yes, because greywater often contains surfactants that might enhance water repellency in soils","wrong_answers":["Yes, because the detergents in the greywater can enhance soil disinfection and reduce the number of pathogens","No, because greywater is not contaminated as contaminated as domestic wastewater and thus no impact is expected","Yes, because greywater might form soil crusts due to its low surface tension, resulting from the presence of surfactants"]},{"id":15328,"question":"Small onsite greywater treatment systems are often low tech-low costs units:","correct_answer":"All of the above","wrong_answers":["Because such systems can produce sufficient water quality to meet high standards for unlimited irrigation by most.","Because these systems are often simple to operate and can be used by many people","Because many consider greywater as an effluent stream that does not pose high risks"]},{"id":15329,"question":"Potential advantage/s of reusing greywater is/are:","correct_answer":"All of the above","wrong_answers":["National and personal economical savings","Diminishing waste of freshwater","Reusing nutrients"]},{"id":15330,"question":"'Total suspended solids' is:","correct_answer":"One measure to evaluate the level of water contamination","wrong_answers":["Clogs sprinklers if its concentration is > 10 mg/L","The solid fraction that passes through a 0.45 micron filter","A lengthy analysis that can be substituted after calibration with analysis of electrical conductivity"]},{"id":15331,"question":"Salinity:","correct_answer":"Is the sum of all ions expressed as mg/L and can often be estimated by a simple and quick measure of electrical conductivity","wrong_answers":["Is significantly affected by organic matter as estimated by BOD analysis","Typically decreases in greywater after biological treatment","In greywater is used to reduce the number of pathogens"]},{"id":15332,"question":"Most water on earth is:","correct_answer":"Salty and found in the oceans","wrong_answers":["Stored in the form of ice","Found as groundwater and is often quite difficult to extract","Freshwater that is swiftly contaminated due to anthropogenic activity"]},{"id":15333,"question":"The Global freshwater crisis is a result of:","correct_answer":"Unequal distribution, growing demand and poor management of water resources","wrong_answers":["The increase in water prices","Receiving less rainfall due to global climate change","Saline water intrusion and iceberg melting"]},{"id":15334,"question":"What is embodied energy?","correct_answer":"The energy invested in the extraction, processing and transportation of a material","wrong_answers":["The energy in our bodies","The energy used during the operation of a building","The energy needed to demolish a building"]},{"id":15335,"question":"What is the Greenhouse Effect?","correct_answer":"The trapping of energy within the atmosphere or a building","wrong_answers":["Plants growing nicely","Cities having more glazed buildings","What causes people to feel less productive"]},{"id":15336,"question":"What is off-gassing?","correct_answer":"Emission of gasses from materials","wrong_answers":["The outcome of poor digestion","The emission of gasses from cars","What happens when water boils"]},{"id":15337,"question":"Why are tents appropriate for deserts?","correct_answer":"They are easily collapsible, easily erected, dismantled and transported","wrong_answers":["They provide natural cooling","They are exotic","They can be easily expanded"]},{"id":15338,"question":"What materials are appropriate as insulation?","correct_answer":"Lightweight (e.g., polystyrene, glass wool, sheep wool)","wrong_answers":["Heavyweight (e.g., concrete, steel, stone)","Liquids (e.g., water, oil)","Inorganic (e.g., plastics and other synthetic materials)"]},{"id":15339,"question":"What materials are appropriate as thermal storage?","correct_answer":"Heavyweight (e.g., concrete, steel, stone)","wrong_answers":["Lightweight (e.g., polystyrene, glass wool, sheep wool)","Liquids (e.g., water, oil)","Inorganic (e.g., plastics and other synthetic materials)"]},{"id":15340,"question":"What is a passive building?","correct_answer":"A building which serves as the main collector, storage and distributor of natural energies","wrong_answers":["A building which never initiates anything","A building which uses mechanical components to move the energy from one part of the system, the building, to the other","A building which needs auxiliary energy for heating and cooling"]},{"id":15341,"question":"What is the most appropriate type of window?","correct_answer":"An openable window with external operable shading","wrong_answers":["A fixed window with internal shading","An openable window with external fixed shading","An openable window with no shading"]},{"id":15342,"question":"What is an Urban Heat Island (UHI)?","correct_answer":"A dense area in the center of the city which is hotter during the night than the open surroundings","wrong_answers":["A tropical island with primarily urban settlements on it","An island in the middle of a city park","A green area in the center of the city which is cooler during the day than the surroundings"]},{"id":15343,"question":"Are tall buildings the ultimate solution for an urban future?","correct_answer":"No, unless they are accompanied by infrastructure adaptations, emergency facilities and appropriate energy saving details","wrong_answers":["Yes, provided they have fast enough elevators","No, but they have nice penthouse views and one can enjoy the cool breezes","Yes, because they provide more living space per land area and encourage social intercourse"]},{"id":15344,"question":"What part of the world's population is living in urban areas?","correct_answer":"The world crossed the 50% share and expected to reach 70% within the next couple of decades.","wrong_answers":["In most countries already over 80% of the population lives in urban areas.","Most of the world's population is not living in cities.","About 30% are urbanites."]},{"id":15345,"question":"In what parts of the world the vast majority of the population are already urbanites ?","correct_answer":"North American countries","wrong_answers":["European countries","African countries","Asian countries"]},{"id":15346,"question":"What is the definition of urbanization ?","correct_answer":"All of the above","wrong_answers":["Increasing number of people that live in urban areas","Changing the designation and uses of land, from agriculture, forestry, mining, and other, to industry, commerce, and services.","Changing our way of life, embracing the urban lifestyle."]},{"id":15347,"question":"Urban 'Ecological footprint'","correct_answer":"Answers b + c","wrong_answers":["Is the land within a city on which the urban infrastructure is builds upon.","Captures the overall productive land on which a city relies within and outside the city all over the world.","Captures the land requires to produce the natural resources (food, timber etc.) consumed in the city and the forest area required to sequester carbon dioxide emissions."]},{"id":15348,"question":"Urban and natural systems have several points of resemblances, including:","correct_answer":"All of the above","wrong_answers":["Both rely on energy from external sources.","Both generate waste and treat it within its boundaries.","Both are consist of diverse population."]},{"id":15349,"question":"6. Which of the following factors shapes the rate and magnitude of urban environmental impact and the potential of advancing urban sustainability?","correct_answer":"All of the above","wrong_answers":["Geographical and climatic conditions","Socio-economic","Size"]},{"id":15350,"question":"What measures can local authorities take to advance urban sustainability?","correct_answer":"All of the above","wrong_answers":["Municipalities can use their power as a planning and regulating authority","Municipalities can provide a wide range of services to its residents.","As significant consumers of materials and energy, Municipalities can set an example by advancing sustainability within their branches/facilities"]},{"id":15351,"question":"The Global Greenhouse Gas emissions (GHG) is strongly connected to cities:","correct_answer":"the vast majority of GHG emissions are directly and indirectly connected to cities","wrong_answers":["While indeed cities generate GHG emissions they are highly efficient and therefore responsible for relative small share of the global emissions","Most GHG can be related to food production, and therefore are not connected to cities","Most urban related GHG emissions are connected to cities in low income parts of the world"]},{"id":15352,"question":"What the term 'urban metabolism' means?","correct_answer":"The flow of materials and energy through a city and its related byproducts (i.e., waste)","wrong_answers":["Urban import of materials from different parts of the world","A way to evaluate the quality of life of urban resident","A way to measure urban residents food consumption"]},{"id":15353,"question":"Urban sustainability can be defined as:","correct_answer":"Finding ways to minimize the urban use of natural resources and the generation of waste, while improving urbanites’ quality of life, in a way that does not exceed the carrying capacity of the local, regional, and global ecosystems","wrong_answers":["Finding ways to increase the material prosperity of cities dwellers","Finding ways to advance economic development.","Finding ways to increase urban growth by using as much as possible resources from local and global sources."]},{"id":15354,"question":"During the last 60 years the size of the world's population has:","correct_answer":"Sharply increased from 3 billion people in the 1960's to over 7 billion in recent years","wrong_answers":["Slowly stabilized and in some parts of the world even declined","Increased significantly in developing countries until the end of the 20th century and is currently declining","Increased equally in wealthy and poor nations pushing the overall population to over 7 billion people"]},{"id":15355,"question":"Over the last few centuries, several things have changed in the way human societies depend on and impact ecosystems. Such change consists of:","correct_answer":"","wrong_answers":["A higher consumption than in the past, both per capita and in the aggregate","A significant increase in the spatial separation between humans and ecosystems","Human ingenuity advanced new methods and technologies that allowed human beings to increase production and use resources more efficiently","All of the above"]},{"id":15356,"question":"It was argued that human development relies on different forms of capital:","correct_answer":"Human capital, manmade capital and natural capital","wrong_answers":["Financial capital and work capital","Natural capital and ecosystem services","Manmade capital and education driven capital"]},{"id":15357,"question":"The American ecological economist Herman Daily coined the terms 'empty world' and 'full world'. What was his main argument?","correct_answer":"We are entering the “full world” era, in which human capital has already allowed us to utilize every possible form of natural capital. The limiting factor of continues development may be declining natural capital","wrong_answers":["The 21st century world is filled by too many people vs. the empty world of the past","In an 'empty world' there are very little natural resources available","We are entering the 'empty world' era, in which the world is almost empty from natural resources. The limiting factor of continues development is human capital"]},{"id":15358,"question":"What kind of indirect drivers are shaping human dependence and impact on the natural systems?","correct_answer":"Demographic, economic, socio-political, cultural and religious, science and technology","wrong_answers":["Demographic and economic","Economic, science and technology","Economic, science and technology, natural and genetic"]},{"id":15359,"question":"The demographic transition model divides demographic trends into the following stages:","correct_answer":"The pre-industrial age, the period of mechanization, industrialization, the mature industrial age and the post-industrial age","wrong_answers":["The industrial revolution, the early 20th century, the late 20th century and the beginning of the 21st century","The slow change and the fast change stages","The developing and developed stages"]},{"id":15360,"question":"What was Thomas Malthus main argument?","correct_answer":"He argued that continuous population growth will bring human society to a point of collapse","wrong_answers":["He argued that humans will always find a way to overcome any natural resource shortage","He argued that the human population can grow indefinitely","Answers a + c"]},{"id":15361,"question":"What is the meaning of the term 'the tragedy of the commons'?","correct_answer":"Common properties such as the environment that are not owned by anyone will lead to a stage in which everyone will try to reap the maximum benefits from them, without considering their limits","wrong_answers":["Common properties such as the environment that are commonly managed by governmental agencies are inefficient","Common properties should not be managed","Common properties such as the environment that are managed by small communities may collapse"]},{"id":15362,"question":"Our behavior and its environmental implications is shaped by:","correct_answer":"All of the above","wrong_answers":["Education; awareness; values and beliefs; culture and religion; common social acceptance","Availability, accessibility and quality of infrastructure","Prices and the costs of different activities; the type and effectiveness of the regulation in place, etc."]},{"id":15363,"question":"Sustainable Development has been defined as:","correct_answer":"Development that meets present needs without compromising the ability of future generations to meet their own needs","wrong_answers":["Development that increases economic growth which will in turn contribute to everyone's prosperity","Development that increases the well-being of the present generation without taking into consideration future generations","Development that advances environmental conservation"]},{"id":16059,"question":"Connectivity increases the overall survival and persistence of the species via:","correct_answer":"","wrong_answers":["Increased genetic load","Decreased extincion risk","Establish of new populations","All of the above"]},{"id":16060,"question":"Which of the following processes is not a major factor of biodiversity loss?","correct_answer":"","wrong_answers":["Habitat loss and degradation","Competiton and predation","Overexplotiation of species","Species invasion"]},{"id":16061,"question":"What is thermal capacity?","correct_answer":"The ability to store heat","wrong_answers":["A material's ability to transfer heat through its mass","The ability to impede heat transfer","One of the major determinants of Sick Building Syndrome"]},{"id":16062,"question":"The University of Yale's Environmental Performance Index (EPI):","correct_answer":"Answers a+b","wrong_answers":["Ranks countries' enviormental performances on issues of ecosystems protection and human's health","European countries and other wealthy nations recived the highest scores","Ranks countries' perfomances on high priority enivormental issues only in protection of the ecosystems"]},{"id":18305,"question":"Wildlife-friendly agriculture can increase biodiversity and ecosystem service by:","correct_answer":"answers a+b","wrong_answers":["retaining a mixture of agriculture crops at the landscape scale","reducing the use of biocides and fertilizers","separating between natural habitat elements and agriculture fieds"]},{"id":18306,"question":"pollution sources are often divided into:","correct_answer":"","wrong_answers":["stationary and mobile pollution sources","man-made and natural pollution sources","answers a+b","above and below ground pollution sources"]},{"id":18307,"question":"It is often hard to find and quantify all pathogens in water because:","correct_answer":"All of the above","wrong_answers":["they are present in low numbers","they have limited survival times","there is a large amount of pathogens to analyze"]},{"id":18308,"question":"in the context of urban sustainability, the concept of economies of agglomeration means that:","correct_answer":"Related or nearby activities are more efficient that distant ones and can reduce the urban environmental impact","wrong_answers":["Increasing the volume of production contributes to cost reduction","Distant activities can lower urban environmental impacts","Non of the above"]},{"id":18309,"question":":Biodiversity refers to","correct_answer":"Variability among living organisms from all sources","wrong_answers":["Large-bodied species","Variety of habitats","Richness of all known species"]},{"id":18310,"question":"In accordance with the chapter, diversity is composed of","correct_answer":"Genetic diversity, organismal diversity and ecological diversity","wrong_answers":["Genetic diversity","Organismal diversity","Ecological diversity"]},{"id":18311,"question":"In accordance with the chapter, diversity is composed of","correct_answer":"Genetic diversity, organismal diversity and ecological diversity","wrong_answers":["Genetic diversity","Organismal diversity","Ecological diversity"]},{"id":18312,"question":"A recent summary for Eukaryote species gives lower and upper estimates of","correct_answer":"3.5 and 108 million","wrong_answers":["1 and 5 million","5 and 20 million","100 and 200 million"]},{"id":18313,"question":"Certainty surrounds estimates of the number of","correct_answer":"More certainty about Eukaryotic than Prokaryotic species","wrong_answers":["More certainty about Prokaryotic than Eukaryotic species","Similar certainty exists","Prokaryotic and Eukaryotic species have the same number of species"]},{"id":18314,"question":"New Eukaryotic species are being described, on average, at a rate of","correct_answer":"thirty six species per day","wrong_answers":["one species per day","five species per day","ten species per day"]},{"id":18315,"question":"Practically, which diversity is better documented and often more readily estimated","correct_answer":"Organismal diversity","wrong_answers":["Genetic diversity","Ecological diversity","All are equally documented and described"]},{"id":18316,"question":"In the last 600 million years, the number of species","correct_answer":"Both increased and decreased based on climatic changes and extinction events","wrong_answers":["Remained constant","Increased","Decreased"]},{"id":18317,"question":"Oceans and land water bodies (i.e. marine systems) are","correct_answer":"Especially diverse","wrong_answers":["Moderate in species diversity","Species-poor","Equally diverse as other systems"]},{"id":18318,"question":"The latitudinal gradient in species richness means that","correct_answer":"There is a general increase in species richness towards lower (tropical) latitudes","wrong_answers":["There is a general decrease in species richness towards lower (tropical) latitudes","There is no change in species richness between latitudes","Different gradients in species richness exist without any clear trend"]},{"id":18319,"question":"Species richness from sea level (above and below)","correct_answer":"Shows a pronounced hump-shaped pattern","wrong_answers":["Increases","Decreases","Shows no clear trend"]},{"id":18320,"question":"Proponents of rewilding assert that rewilding will lead to increased biodiversity and ecosystem function","correct_answer":"True","wrong_answers":["False"]},{"id":18321,"question":"The definition of rewilding has evolved since its inception. Today rewilding focuses on:","correct_answer":"Species introduction or reintroduction as a way to restore ecosystem functioning through the facilitation of assumed natural processes that existed before the ecosystems were altered by human impacts correct","wrong_answers":["Restoring self-regulated ecosystems","Mimicking the aims of restoration ecology","“Naturalized grazing” (rewilding without predators) as a means to preserve and develop particular kinds of landscapes"]},{"id":18322,"question":"Rewilding strategies include","correct_answer":"All of the above correct","wrong_answers":["Passive rewilding","Pleistocene rewilding","Translocation rewilding"]},{"id":18323,"question":"The challenges of rewilding include","correct_answer":"All of the above","wrong_answers":["The difficulty to accurately predict the impacts of predator or dominant herbivore introduction on a community or ecosystem","Rewilding can produce unintended consequences such as diseases","Passive rewilding results in an increase of water consumption by trees, thus reducing water availability to humans"]},{"id":18324,"question":"What is PM?","correct_answer":"Particles","wrong_answers":["Combined Smoke and Fog","Waste","Gaseous species"]},{"id":18325,"question":"Tiny particles are harmful","correct_answer":"In case we inhale them","wrong_answers":["If we touch them with our hands","Only if they are within the nanoscale range","Only if they are from combustion"]},{"id":18326,"question":"PM2.5 are called fine particles","correct_answer":"Fine means very small","wrong_answers":["As they are fine and are not harmful","As they are not spherical","None of the above"]},{"id":18327,"question":"PM10 refers to","correct_answer":"Particles of less than 10 microns in size","wrong_answers":["Particles from the 10 most dangerous sources","All particles above 10 microns","Measurement systems that can measure particles of less than 10 microns"]},{"id":18328,"question":"Air pollution comes from","correct_answer":"All of the above","wrong_answers":["Man-made systems","Natural sources","Chemical reactions"]},{"id":18329,"question":"The smaller the particle","correct_answer":"The more dangerous it is<del> correct</del>","wrong_answers":["The faster it falls to the ground","The more visible it is","All of the above"]},{"id":18330,"question":"Smoke particles originate from","correct_answer":"","wrong_answers":["Vehicle engines","Dust storms","Acid rain","Marine aerosols"]},{"id":18331,"question":"Air pollution","correct_answer":"All of the above","wrong_answers":["Can harm our health","Can harm vegetation","Can reduce visibility"]},{"id":18332,"question":"Design and construction in the near future will be challenged by the following decisive processes","correct_answer":"Accelerated urbanization in developing countries, depletion of fossil fuels and other natural resources and the impact of human activities on the environment","wrong_answers":["Development of high tech solutions to high construction","Development of advanced technologies for massive construction in developed countries","New architectural and urban planning styles"]},{"id":18333,"question":"Old buildings need retrofitting because","correct_answer":"They are usually poorly insulated and not airtight.","wrong_answers":["They tend to be ugly by today’s standards and this can improve their looks","They have faulty kitchen equipment","They do not meet modern client expectations and thus their value is low"]},{"id":18334,"question":"What are solar and wind rights","correct_answer":"The right of a building or open space to free solar access in winter and free access to cool winds during the hot seasons","wrong_answers":["Constitutional rights of the individual, protected by a country’s laws","Rights one buys together with real estate","An expression that signifies something imaginary and non-tangible (like the light and the wind)"]},{"id":18335,"question":"?What is SBS","correct_answer":"Sick Building Syndrome","wrong_answers":["A car company","Sunny Building Style","A behavioral matter"]},{"id":18336,"question":"How much energy is used by buildings in their whole life cycle, including construction, operation and demolition\n (stated as percentage of the overall energy used in industrialized countries)?","correct_answer":"","wrong_answers":["20-30%","50-70%","10-30%","40-50%"]},{"id":18337,"question":"?What is the share of earth land mass on which cities are built","correct_answer":"2.8%","wrong_answers":["10.5%","25%","50%"]},{"id":18338,"question":"?In what part of the world are most of the largest 100 cities located","correct_answer":"Asia","wrong_answers":["Africa","North America","Europe"]},{"id":18339,"question":"Urban activities can be associated with environmental impacts at the","correct_answer":"Local, regional and global spatial scales","wrong_answers":["Local scale","Local and regional spatial scales","Global scale"]},{"id":18340,"question":"What are the main environmental related impacts of low income cities","correct_answer":"","wrong_answers":["Poor water systems","Failing sanitary conditions","High rates of Greenhouse Gases (GHG) emissions","Answers a + b"]},{"id":18341,"question":"? What are the indirect drivers of urban environmental impact","correct_answer":"All of the above","wrong_answers":["Demography","Affluence","Inequality"]},{"id":18342,"question":":The ecological footprint of cities includes","correct_answer":"The productive area of land required to supply the demand for renewable resources and sequester its waste","wrong_answers":["The area within the city on which urban activities impact","The land area surrounding the city","The implications of the urban activities on biodiversity"]},{"id":18343,"question":": It has been argued that","correct_answer":"Two thirds of total consumption and pollution can be traced to cities in rich countries","wrong_answers":["Two thirds of the global pollution can be traced to cities in Asia and Africa","Most resources consumption and pollution is connected to the emerging mega-cities in different parts of the world","Cities in Affluent countries (e.g., North America, European Union, Japan, Australia) having the smallest impact on the global scale"]},{"id":18345,"question":"?What are the main environmental impacts of high income cities","correct_answer":"Answers b + c","wrong_answers":["High income cities managed to minimize their overall environmental impacts","High income cities main pressure is connected to the rates of resources consumption","High income cities are generating large amounts of GHG emissions"]},{"id":18346,"question":":The 'Urban Sustainability Multiplier' suggests that","correct_answer":"The concentration of cities infrastructure can be used as a mean to minimize the urban environmental impact","wrong_answers":["The way cities function today is key to advance urban sustainability","The larger a city is, the more sustainable it is","Multiplying the number of people living in cities by their use of resources signal the rate of urban sustainability"]},{"id":19439,"question":"The percentage of the ecosystem services evaluated in the MEA that are being degraded or used unsustainably is, approximately","correct_answer":"","wrong_answers":["30%","40%","50%","60%"]},{"id":19440,"question":"Between 1960-2000, while the world population doubled and the global economy increased more than sixfold, food production increased by roughly","correct_answer":"Two-and-a-half times","wrong_answers":["Twice","Three times","Ten times"]},{"id":19441,"question":"Currently, the overexploitation and depletion of important commercial fish stocks are estimated to be","correct_answer":"25%","wrong_answers":["10%","15%","20%"]},{"id":19442,"question":"The estimated loss of forest area during the industrial era is","correct_answer":"40%","wrong_answers":["30%","50%","60%"]},{"id":19443,"question":"Species extinction and overharvesting of medicinal plants…","correct_answer":"…are diminishing the availability of these resources","wrong_answers":["…are contributing to the future maintenance of these resources","…are increasing the probability of finding these resources in the future","…are beneficial for combatting the increase of diseases"]},{"id":19444,"question":"Tropical deforestation and desertification have had an effect on local rainfall by","correct_answer":"Reducing it","wrong_answers":["Increasing it","Stabilizing it","Having no effect"]},{"id":19445,"question":"Pesticide use in agricultural areas","correct_answer":"Decreases the capacity of agroeosystems to provide pest control","wrong_answers":["Does not have any effect","Does not change the capacity of agroeosystems to provide pest control","Increases natural pest control"]},{"id":19446,"question":"Since the 1940s, changes to ecosystems","correct_answer":"Have contributed to a significant rise in the number of floods and major wildfires","wrong_answers":["Have contributed to a significant rise only in the number of floods","Have contributed to a significant rise only in major wildfires","Have not changed the number of floods and major wildfires"]},{"id":19447,"question":"The modification of an ecosystem to alter one ecosystem service","correct_answer":"Generally results in changes to other ecosystem services as well","wrong_answers":["Generally results in changes to that ecosystem service alone","Has effects on all the other ecosystem services","Has no effects on other ecosystem services"]},{"id":19448,"question":"Actions to conserve or enhance a particular component of an ecosystem or its services may","correct_answer":"Benefit other services","wrong_answers":["Not benefit other services","Benefit exclusively these services","Not benefit the stakeholders"]},{"id":19449,"question":"The acronym PM stands for","correct_answer":"Particulate matter","wrong_answers":["Particles under 10 microns in size","Pulsation method for trapping particles","None of the above"]},{"id":19450,"question":"Particles in the air come from","correct_answer":"All of the above","wrong_answers":["Dust storms","Combustion","Industry"]},{"id":19469,"question":"The following are conventional water sources:","correct_answer":"Shallow well water and surface water","wrong_answers":["Treated wastewater and deep groundwater","Rainwater harvesting and dew collection","Surface water and saline water"]},{"id":19470,"question":"The followings are alternative (new) water sources:","correct_answer":"","wrong_answers":["Well water and surface water","Treated wastewater and groundwater","Rainwater harvesting and dew collection","Surface water and saline water"]},{"id":19471,"question":"In order to use alternative water sources, one should:","correct_answer":"Ensure proper regulation, change public perception and create a link between market needs and research","wrong_answers":["Develop appropriate pumps, disseminate knowledge via pamphlet distribution and workshops","Do nothing, as using alternative water sources is basically similar to current practices, and other than minor adjustments no changes are needed","It is impossible to use alternative water resources as the technology is not available yet"]},{"id":19472,"question":"What is the global estimated of land that is irrigated with untreated wastewater?","correct_answer":"Between 4-20 million hectares","wrong_answers":["None","Most of the agriculture products are irrigated with wastewater","No such estimate is available"]},{"id":19473,"question":"If you were an irrigation expert, would you recommend irrigating with untreated (raw) wastewater?","correct_answer":"No, despite its benefits it might pose severe health risks that should be addressed, so wastewater should be sufficiently treated before it can be safely reused","wrong_answers":["Yes; it creates jobs and may alleviate poverty as well as enhance global food security","No, wastewater should not be reused","There is no reason to deal with it as the overall volume of wastewater is so small that its contribution is negligible."]},{"id":19474,"question":"What is expected to improve if significant technologies concerning water demand and use will be developed?","correct_answer":"Water management, in terms of efﬁciency and effectiveness, with the related beneﬁts of economic development and decent jobs.","wrong_answers":["Water cycling that can even affect global climate changes","Even if significant technological advances occur, the water sector is not a significant one and therefore overall, no significant improvements are expected","Improvements in the water sector are going to have an almost immediate impact on most industries in the form of a chain reaction"]},{"id":19475,"question":"Why should innovation in the water sectors be introduced with caution?","correct_answer":"Because innovation can also have negative impacts, such as destroying jobs and affectimg many people","wrong_answers":["Because Intelligent monitoring networks may be attacked by cyber hackers and ruin essential water distribution","Because innovation in the water sector may slow down other innovations in other important sectors such as the energy and electricity","Because many countries will struggle to control water demand"]},{"id":19476,"question":"According to the text, water monitoring refers to:","correct_answer":"All of the above","wrong_answers":["Quality","Quantity","Vulnerability"]},{"id":19477,"question":"Policy and water management can impact the water-Jobs nexus by:","correct_answer":"All of the above","wrong_answers":["Ensuring the sustainability of water resources and ecosystems","Development and operation of water infrastructure","Capacity building of human resources as well as increasing knowledge"]},{"id":19478,"question":"The size of the world population around the year 1700 is estimated at","correct_answer":"600 million people","wrong_answers":["1 million people","3 billion people","100 million people"]},{"id":19479,"question":"At the beginning of the 21st century, the world's population already reached the size of:","correct_answer":"7 billion people","wrong_answers":["2 billion people","10 billion people","900 million people"]},{"id":19480,"question":"Two main revolutions allowed the of human population to grow fast and reach its current size:","correct_answer":"The agricultural and industrial revolutions","wrong_answers":["The French and American revolutions","The agriculture and green revolutions","The industrial and robotics revolutions"]},{"id":19481,"question":"For most human history, the carrying capacity for humans and other animals was:","correct_answer":"Quite similar in most cases","wrong_answers":["Very different. Animals' carrying capacity was much higher","Different. Humans managed to get more resources and therefore to have a higher carrying capacity","Animals were part of the natural system and therefore the carrying capacity was different from that of humans"]},{"id":19482,"question":"Before the industrial revolution, birth rates and family size were:","correct_answer":"High birth rates and quite large families, as children were part of the work force","wrong_answers":["Very low, as people did not have enough food, they chose to have small families","Very low, as people worked so hard they did not have time to have large families","Answers a + b"]},{"id":19483,"question":"In recent decades, most of the world population growth is happening in:","correct_answer":"The poor (developing) nations","wrong_answers":["China","The wealthy (developed) nations.","The U.S and E.U."]},{"id":19484,"question":"What factor/s allowed the fast growth of the human population during the 20th century:","correct_answer":"Answers b + c","wrong_answers":["Better education systems","Modern public health systems","Improved sanitation and access to clean water"]},{"id":19485,"question":"What was the contribution of the green revolution to population growth?","correct_answer":"","wrong_answers":["The green revolution used modern plant breeding to create high-yield varieties and therefore increase the availability of food all around the world","The green revolution increased environmental awareness, which contributed to the advancement of environmental policy. Such policy managed to reduce the number of people affected by environmental degradation and pollution","The green revolution involved the increase use of fertilizers and pesticide, which contributed to humans' health and well-being","Answers b + c"]},{"id":19486,"question":"Human population regulation is:","correct_answer":"Answers b + c","wrong_answers":["A relatively new concept that is relevant to the effort of governments in recent decades to control population growth","Traditional societies in different parts of the world had various social mechanisms to regulate population size","Natural / environmental factors such as land and water availability, climate etc. contributed to human population regulation throughout human history"]},{"id":19487,"question":"Environmental refugees are:","correct_answer":"People that have to migrate mostly from traditional rural areas because the environmental conditions cannot support their needs","wrong_answers":["People who choose to leave polluted parts of the city to cleaner neighborhoods","People with high environmental awareness that are worried by ongoing environmental degradation processes","Environmentalists that are forced by governments to leave their territories"]},{"id":27359,"question":"What the term “economies of scale” means?","correct_answer":"Related or nearby activities are more efficient than distant ones, and can lower the production costs.","wrong_answers":[".....","....."]},{"id":27360,"question":"In the species-area relationship curve, high 'Z' values (e.g., 0.6) reflects the\nsampling of species in:","correct_answer":"","wrong_answers":[]},{"id":58149,"question":"Which of the following polluting groups is typical for greywater?","correct_answer":"Physicochemical parameters and microbiological parameters","wrong_answers":["Ecological parameters","Microbiological parameters","Physicochemical parameters"]},{"id":58150,"question":"Ecosystem services are:","correct_answer":"The benefits people obtain from ecosystems.","wrong_answers":["Products obtained from ecosystems.","Benefits obtained from the regulation of ecosystem processes.","Combination of natural habitat area and agricultural fields."]},{"id":58151,"question":"גרסה מתוקנת: What the term “economies of scale” means?\n(גרסה מתוקנת לשאלה קיימת)","correct_answer":"Describes systems in which scaling up can justify the use of measures that can reduce environmental impact.","wrong_answers":["Related or nearby activities are more efficient than distant ones, and can lower the production costs.","Human ingenuity advanced new methods and technologies that allowed human.","All answers are incorrect."]},{"id":58152,"question":"In the species-area relationship curve, high 'Z' values (e.g,0.6) reflects the sampling of species in:\n(גרסה מתוקנת לשאלה קיימת)","correct_answer":"Mainlands (provinces).","wrong_answers":["Contiguous extents.","Ecological islands.","All answers are incorrect."]},{"id":58343,"question":"how many mass extiction events occurred in the past?","correct_answer":"","wrong_answers":["10"]},{"id":58344,"question":"definition of smog is?","correct_answer":"a combination of gaseous species and particles","wrong_answers":["a fog created above the ocean","a city in ancient sumar","an extinct dragon species"]},{"id":58345,"question":"thermal comfort is defined as:","correct_answer":"mind state that expresses satification with thermal enviroment and is assessed by subjective evaluation","wrong_answers":["animal body fat percentage","the temperature range in which most animals lives in comfort","the ability of a species to live in thermal equilibrium"]},{"id":58346,"question":"The american ecologist Herman Daly uses the term \"empty world\" and \"full world\" in order to:","correct_answer":"explain the relationship between human capital and natural capital","wrong_answers":["explain the relationship between the human world and natural world","explain the relationship between capitalism and socialism","explain the relationship between area and species diversity"]},{"id":98180,"question":"The authors of the article:","correct_answer":"Recommend revisiting the critical assumptions of rewilding and identifying its limitations","wrong_answers":["Urge the widespread implementation of rewilding","Consider rewilding to be a new potential panacea for restoring biodiversity in the wilderness","Suggest that rewilding should take over as a major paradigm in conservation"]},{"id":139636,"question":"Demographic factor that can lead to extinction may include:","correct_answer":"Low reproductive rate and low survival rates","wrong_answers":["high reproductive rate and low survival rates","all answers are incorrect","all answers are correct"]},{"id":139638,"question":"The dramatic air pollution in London in 1952:","correct_answer":"Lasted for 3 weeks and cased the deaths of more than 5,000 people","wrong_answers":["Lasted for 3 months and cased the deaths of more than 10,000 people","Lasted for 3 years and cased the deaths of more than 5,000 people","Lasted for 3 years and cased the deaths of more than 10,000 people"]},{"id":141786,"question":"?\"what is the link between \"thermal conductivity\" and \"thermal insulation","correct_answer":"Thermal insulation is the opposite of thermal conductivity","wrong_answers":["Wool is characterized by both thermal insulation and thermal conductivity","Thermal insulation is the is the same as thermal conductivity","Cement and steel are characterized by both thermal insulation and thermal conductivity"]},{"id":141792,"question":"The case of food in cities is an example for:","correct_answer":"The singnificant reliance of cities on global ecosystems","wrong_answers":["The efficiency of cities in supporting their own needs","The singnificant reliance of cities on provisinning services"]}];